（カブト）チッ…。
（ガイ／リー）うぉ～！
（リー）なんて凶悪な風貌。
It has such a fiendish appearance!
（ガイ）極悪人だろ　キサマ。
You're real bad news,
aren't you?!
（カカシ）ソイツは　九尾化したナルトだ。
（２人）えっ？
That's Naruto transformed
into the Nine Tails.
Huh?!
（カカシ）もっとも
影分身とも違うようだが。
Although it's different from
a Shadow Clone.
（ネジ）ものすごい九尾のチャクラだ。
The Nine Tails' chakra is immense!
本物と変わらないクローンさ。
It's a clone that's no different
from the real thing.
ついでに　九尾のチャクラまで
一緒に複製したみたいだけどね。
Not only that,
it even seems to have
copied the Nine Tails' chakra.
（キバ）はぁ！！
（シカマル）チッ。
（ヒナタ）ナルト君！
Naruto!
飛段を生んだ　まやかしか…
いつ　ナルトに仕込んだ？
A counterfeit, eh...
like the way Hidan was created.
When did you do it to Naruto?
ほんの偶然さ。
It was by chance.
まあ　結果は
僕も想定外だったけど。
And I never expected these results.
逃がさんぞ。
I won't let you get away!
フッ。
楽しいことになりそうだ。
This is going to be...
quite amusing.
うわぁ！
うおっ　とう！
おぉ～！
フン！　うおっ！
（テンテン）はぁっ！！
うわっ！
ああ！
（ドック）これが忍の戦い…。
This is... how shinobi fight...
（レオ）すげぇ！
（みんな）うわっ！
Awesome!
（ガイ）リー　やるぞ。
（リー）はい！
Lee, let's do it!
Right!
はぁ！！
うぉ～！！
おぉ～！！
うわぁ！
…らを…。
More...
もっと…。
力を！
power!
（ヒナタ）きゃっ！
（ネジ）ヒナタ様！
Lady Hinata!
力！
Power!
（九尾）おもしろい
おもしろいぞ。
Good... This is good...
（九尾）喜んで　チャクラをくれてやる。
I'm more than happy to
give you more chakra!
うわぁ！
A person?
うわっ！
It's a person.
He fell from the sky?
That's...!
（カカシ）あれは！
What was that?!
（飛段）なんだ？
Kakashi!
カカシ…　よし！
俺たちも住人を助けるぞ。
All right! We're going to
rescue the townspeople.
うわぁ～！
Shiseru!
シセル！　子供たちを！
Take care of the kids!
Brother!
（シセル）お兄ちゃん！
（シセル）さあ！
Let's go!
Shiseru...!
（ランド）シセルさん。
Naruto, Naruto!
ナルト君　ナルト君　ナルト君！
あっ！
— Sensei!
先生！
always chasing after your shadow
itsu made mo oikakete iru anata no zanzo wo
when you dream, your face looks like it did before
yume ni miru yokogao ha ano koro no mama de
you run into the tall grass and disappear
se no takai kusanami ni hashiri satte kieta
I push through the memories and follow you
omoidasu kioku wo kakewake atoo uboku ha
it's frustrating as I run out of breath and in the end I'm unable to reach you
modokashiku mo iki wo kirashite saigo ha todokazu ni
far away
tooku
how many years ago was it?
nannenmae no koto desho
I left my heart at that place
nidoto modorenai ano basho ni
where I can never return
oite kite shimatta boku no kokoro sa
if this is a dream, if I can't get it back
moshimo yume naraba tori modosenai no nara
then how can I tell you how I feel?
kono kimochi ha do shite utaereba ii no
I'm still chasing after the shadow from that day
imadani oikakete iru ano hi no zanzo wo
though I spend my days in sorrow
kanashimi ni ake kurenagara mo ima
I'll live on in this world without you
anata naki sekai de boku wa ikiru yo
Great...
That's brilliant, Naruto.
Destroy.
どいてくれ！
すみません！
はい　気づいたときには→
町長はどこにも…。
Destroy...
ご無事でいらっしゃると
よいのですが…。
そうですね。
...the world!
あっ…　すみません。
皆さん　朗報です。
幸いにも
死者は出なかったようです。
Out of the way!
よかった。
（サイ）でも　ナルトとドックさんは？
Excuse us!
Yes, and then we became aware...
that the village chief was
nowhere to be found.
（ナルト）おっちゃん…。
I just hope that he's all right.
ナルト君！
I hope so too.
（カカシ）踏み潰される瞬間に
大蛇のようなものを見たと→
Excuse me...
シセルさんが言っていた。
死体もないし　おそらく…。
カブトの手中に…。
Good news, everyone!
（ヤマト）戦闘中に　急に
暁連中を収監したのも→
There were no fatalities!
本来の目的を
達成したからですね。
That's a relief...
But what about Naruto and Dokku?
ここは？
（ドック）わかんない。
気づいたら　もういたんだ。
Mister?
Naruto!
待ってて。
According to Shiseru, just as
they were about to be trampled,
うわ～っ！
something like
a giant snake appeared.
There were no bodies,
so in all likelihood...
（ネジ）それと　あの
クローンとかいう九尾→
Kabuto has them.
Akatsuki members suddenly stopped
in the middle of fighting...
なぜか　急速に
力を失っていった。
Which means Kabuto
achieved his goals.
（カカシ）カブトも制御に
手こずっていたようだし→
Where are we?
おそらく
不完全な状態なんだろう。
I don't know.
When I came to,
I found myself here.
（ヤマト）そもそも
ヤツの目的は何なんだ？
Wait...
穢土転生した
忍たちのレベルからして→
マジで戦っているようには
見えねえしな。
本当　無事でよかったわ！
ありがとう。
And the Nine Tails clone
or whatever...
It lost its power quickly.
それじゃあ。
はい。
（サクラ）シセルさん。
Kabuto seemed to have
a hard time controlling it.
そうね　信じるしかないわね。
He probably hasn't perfected
the process yet.
２人が無事でいてくれることを。
Just what was his objective
in the first place?
お兄ちゃん…。
Compared to the level of
the Reanimated Shinobi,
they didn't seem to
be fighting seriously.
子供たちは？
（シセル）ミィナが　血や
ケガをした人を怖がるんで→
I'm so glad that you're not hurt.
いったん　家に連れて帰ったの。
Thank you.
Take care...
Yes.
Shiseru...
I guess we just have
to have faith...
that those two are all right.
Brother...
Where are the kids?
Mina gets scared at the sight
of blood and injured people,
so I took her home for now.
（九尾）フフフ…。
（九尾）もう　認めろ
あれは　お前の本性だ。
ワシとお前は　一心同体。
さあ　その身を委ねろ。
ワシを解放しろ！
Accept it...
That is your true nature.
（ミナト）ナルト。
ナルト君　ナルト君！　大丈夫？
You and I are of
one mind, one body.
構うな！
So...
give in to me.
SEAL
Free...
すまねえ…。
me!
((ミィナ：出てけ　出てけ　出てけ！
Naruto...
出てけ　出てけ！
ミィナちゃん　ミィナちゃん！
Naruto, Naruto...
（シセル）ミィナ！
Are you all right?
Leave me alone!
Sorry about that.
Get out!
— Mina! Mina!
- Get out! Get out, get out!
（シセル）ああ　やっちゃった。
Get out, get out!
Mina!
ホントの母親でもないのに
マジで引っぱたいちゃった。
それは　キミが　あの子たちと
本気で接しているからだと思う。
でも　僕は　ミィナが→
村でのあの子を
よく知ってるから。
あんなことを言ったり
する子じゃないって。
きっと　なんか別の理由が…。
Oh dear, what have I done...
I'm not even her mother.
But I slapped her very hard.
やっぱり
施設に預けるべきだよね。
I think you did that because
you truly care about her.
あの子たちのためにも。
But I know Mina well...
from the time
we were in the village.
僕も　ずっと　キミには
甘えてはいられない。
She wouldn't do that.
She's not like that.
I'm sure there's a reason.
私…　私ね
あの子たち引き取って→
I guess letting the facility take
the kids in is the right thing to do.
It's in their best interest.
一緒に住めればいいなって
思ってたの。
みんなと　ワイワイやって→
笑ったり　一緒に泣いたり
ときどき　ケンカしたりしてね。
Besides...I can't keep relying
on you.
でね　いつも
誰かさんがそばにいて…。
I...
Actually, I was thinking
how nice it would be
to take the kids and live together.
ダメかな？
How lively it would be...
All the laughter and the tears...
and the occasional fights...
And if someone were
to always be by my side...
お兄ちゃんのままでもいいから。
Would you be against it?
ダメ？
もしかして　まだ　気にしてる？
あれは　お兄ちゃんのせい
なんかじゃないのに。
もう　全然　平気だから。
You can stay my "Brother."
そんなこと言うなよ。
What do you say?
産めなくなったんだぞ。
You're still not...
Do you still blame yourself
for that?
It wasn't your fault!
(ごめんなさい…))
どうか　どうか　みんな無事で…。
Everything's okay!
すまねえ　おっちゃん。
俺のせいだ。
アイツも俺だ。
Don't say that.
俺の中に潜んでる
もう１つの本性なんだ。
You can't have children
because of that...
おばさんや　あの子たちに
何かあったら　俺…。
I'm sorry...
違うよ！　キミは
利用されただけじゃないか！
Please... Please let
everyone be safe.
あれは　キミなんかじゃない。
あんな姿や…。
Sorry, mister.
あれは　俺だ！
（九尾）殺す　壊す　何もかも！
I'm to blame.
He's part of me.
わしが　すべてを！
He exists deep inside me...
It's my other nature.
If anything happens to
Auntie or the kids...
in
Ten...
サクラ　準備をしろ。
You're wrong.
You were used!
もうすぐ出立する。
はい。
That's not you.
Not that—
でも　どこへ？
ホールだ。
That thing is me!
恐らく　カブトは　そこにいる。
I'll kill... I'll destroy... everything!
私も！
私も　ぜひ　同行させてください。
I will destroy it all!
忍の皆さんからすると→
足手まといになるかも
しれませんが…。
そんなことありませんよ。
大切な人を思う気持は
よくわかります。
一緒に行きましょう。
Sakura...
Get ready. We leave shortly.
Yes, sir.
But where are we going?
To the "Hole."
Kabuto is probably there.
I'm going with you!
Please let me come.
確かに　キミのような
とてもすごい力を持つ人は→
You're shinobi, so I'll probably
be a nuisance, but...
その力を正しく使えても
悪いことに使っても→
You'll be no such thing.
その結果には　大きな責任を
負わないといけないと思う。
We understand what caring
for someone means.
Let's go together!
でも　キミが力を…。
強くなりたいと思ったのは
どうして？
People like you with
immense power...
仲間を　大切な人たちを→
Even if you choose to use
that power for good or evil...
守りたい。
you still have to shoulder the weight
of having such a huge responsibility.
友達を　助けたい。
What made you want
to become stronger?
その強い思いが　キミを→
キミの力を→
Was it your desire for power?
きっと導いてくれる。
((ミナト：迷うな。
To protect... my friends...
those dear to me.
お前を…。
(信じてる))
I want to... save my friends...
拾っておいたよ。
No doubt it's that intense desire...
that is guiding your strength.
キミを…。
キミの正しい力を→
信じてる。
Do not waver.
先生　助けにいこう。
I believe...
in you!
（ファズ）ムチャだよ　殺されるよ。
（ソラ）危ないわ。
それに　シセルさんが
ここで待ってろって。
僕ら　先生がいなかったら
死んでた。
I picked it up for you.
I believe in you...
それに…。
I believe in your power...
アイツらの欲しがってるものを
持ってる。
in the good inside you!
そいつと　先生を交換してもらう。
Let's go save Sensei!
That's crazy, we'll be killed.
今度は　僕らが先生を助ける番だ。
It's too dangerous.
Besides, Shiseru told us
to wait here.
Without Sensei,
we'd be dead.
うん。
And...
行こう！
I have what those guys want.
でも　どこへ？
行く場所なんて決まってる。
僕たちの村。
We'll ask them to
return Sensei for these!
This time, it's our turn
to save Sensei!
（ドック）町長！？
（ディソナス）もう茶番はやめだ。
Uh-huh!
Yeah!
町役場のバカが
国に報告などしなければ→
Uh-huh!
Let's go!
— Okay!
とっくに
ケリがついていたものを…。
But go where?
お前。
Where else?
お前は　持っている　ねの価値を
わかってるのか？
Back to our village!
Chief?!
Enough of this farce!
If that fool from the town hall
hadn't reported this to the government,
everything would be
over and done with.
You...
Do you even know
the value of that "sound"
you have in your possession?
"SAEZURI"
"POWER"
I wonder why I can't fly
nande kanaa sora ga tobenai no wa
even though in my dreams, I have wings
yume no naka no boku wa hane ga haeten no ni
I'm going to surpass my limits and leave this place
genkai wo koete tobidasou koko kara
I'll drive away my loneliness with you
samishisa fuki tobasu kimi to kimi to
"I love you" and "good bye" have disappeared
i love you mo sayonara mo ienakatta
leaving me here incomplete
koko ni fukanzen na boku dake wo nokoshite
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
you still haven't taught me the song of love
ai no uta kimi ni mada tsutaetenai yo
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１１組の皆さんによる→
of this dazzling world
dokomademo mabushiku kagayaku sekai wo
of this song
kono uta wo
Next Episode
I'll get him!
Amazing! Amazing!
This is amazing!
This is impressive...
This is the "Ama no Hoko"?
Up to now, I've been taught
a lot of important things
from a lot of people...
I won't give up now that
we've come this far!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Power — Episode 5"
Next Episode
My power is...!